and suffer a lot
是很痛苦的
but later on, I realized
然后后来我就发现
that I had received so much encouragement and love from a young age
就是因为我从小到大得到了太多的鼓励与爱
so my love just overflowed
所以我的这个爱都他妈荡漾出来了
which is why I was able to stay positive even when my life situations became really tough later on
所以在我后来的人生境遇非常的不爽的时候
I still feel that destiny is so clear.
我仍然感觉到啊这个天命昭昭
I feel particularly encouraged.
感觉到特别的啊受到鼓励
I believe I can definitely get out of this predicament.
我认为自己是一定能够脱出险境的
I can definitely save myself.
一定能自己救助自己的
But is it all my doing?
但实际上都是我的功劳吗
My family
我的家人
My friends
我的朋友
My mentors
我的这些师长
All these people have given me positive encouragement.
我的所有这些人他都给我都是正向的鼓励
But you'll find that life, in many ways, is about
但你会发现人生到头来就是很多的时候来讲
when you truly need someone's help,
你在真正需要别人的时候
you don't get it.
你得不到帮助
Why is there such a big difference between people?
为什么人与人之间的差异特别大呢
It's because we all have different experiences and feelings. But life doesn't give you a second chance to start over. So what are you going to do? The meaning of life, as I see it, lies in intense self-deception.
就是因为我们所有的这种经历感受不一样 但是人生又没有办法从头来来 那你该怎么办呢 就是人生的意义就像我说的一样 在于高强度的自我欺骗
This world is inherently virtual
这个世界本来就是虚拟的
Our planet operates within this universe
我们的星球运营在这个宇宙当中
which is an extremely rare event
是一个极小概率事件
So a lot of things are a matter of mind over matter
所以很多东西都是心想事成啊
If I had such an experience
如果我有这种经历
it would make my body feel quite joyful
导致了我的身体是比较愉快的
giving me a lot of positive feedback
给我很多正向反馈
So if you think the same way
那你也这么想
you can also attain these things
你也可以得到这些东西
It's about reprogramming yourself
就是给自己重新再编程
First, you need to understand that you are incredibly valuable
你首先要明白你自己是非常非常有价值的啊
You can't do it
你不行
I'll rewire your thinking
我就给你洗脑
It's okay
没关系
Just hand over your mind to me for a moment
你就把你的脑子暂时交给我
Let's see why you are valuable
你看你为什么是有价值的
First, come over here and look
首先你来这看
You belong to the top 6.5 percent in China
你就是属于中国的百分之前6.5的人
And you are among the top 650
而你在这前650当中
Are you the last one?
你是最后一名吗
You're not
你也不是
And you've successfully made it this far
而且你成功的活到了这么大了
So why does this pessimism insist on belittling you?
为什么这幽记主义他一定要贬低你呢
He says he always hopes you will improve
他说我总是希望你能进步
But in reality, people can't always be put down Can't always be pessimistic Then after you filter through people You need to treat people as they are. You need to communicate with others. Actually, scoring 94 is also great. Not getting a perfect score is also fine.
但实际上人不能总是在贬低 不能总是忧寄主义 然后你去筛选完人了以后 你要把人还原 你要把人跟人说啊 其实考94分也很好 没有考到100分也很好
This world isn't just for those who score 100.
这世界上不是说只有考到100分的才是人
So many parents,
所以很多人的家长
their families of origin are pretty messed up,
他的原生家庭就比较操蛋啊
and haven't given them much encouragement.
就没有给他很好的鼓励
They are just conditioning their own children.
都是在驯化自己的孩子
Playing the Confucian game
玩儒家那一套
My own level isn't high
自己的水平不高
Yet I still try to mold others
还要驯化别人
That's why many people suffer
所以这就是导致很多人很痛苦的原因
Just because they live in an East Asian society
就因为生活在东亚这种社会里边
It leads to the creation of many hollow individuals
就会产生出很多的空心人来
There's no way around it
这是没有办法的事情
But the education I received from my family was completely different
但是我家庭给我的教育完全就不是这样
So let me tell you
所以我跟你讲
Different families can be so different.
不同的家庭真的完全不一样
Happy families are all alike.
幸福的家庭千篇一律
Every unhappy family is unhappy in its own way.
不幸的家庭有各自的不幸
So, friends,
所以朋友们
Comrades,
同志们
Just think about it,
你仔细想想啊
You call me Cyber Godfather,
你们叫我一句赛博义父
I can't just let you call me that for nothing,
我不能白让你们叫
Right?
对不对
First, you need to understand
首先你就要明白
in this universe
在这个宇宙当中
the probability of a life being born is extremely low
诞生一个生命的概率是非常的低的
your existence
你的出现
being born into this world is a very rare occurrence your universe begins with you and ends with you if you feel unhappy if you want to start over This universe would have no meaning. All of this would be meaningless to you.
你的这个投胎就是一个非常不容易的事情 你的宇宙以你为开始 以你为结束 你感觉到不爽 你想重开 这宇宙就没意义了 这一切对你没有意义
So, you are the master of everything.
所以你是一切的主宰
This is the second person, to begin with.
这是首先的第二人
As long as you're alive, there is meaning.
只要活着就有意义
The meaning of life is something you give to yourself.
人的意义是自己给自己的
So, you are inherently good.
所以你本身就很好
It's not about what you do being good.
不是在于你做了什么事情很好
It's not about doing something great
不是在于你做了什么伟大的事情
and then getting some result
然后就怎么怎么样
Being alive
人活着
human existence itself
human being就是存在
is a wonderful thing
存在就是很好
you live in this world
你在这世界上生活
you pay to breathe
花钱呼吸
you walk among people
你在人群当中行走
you are creating value
你就是在创造价值
You're also creating fertilizer when you poop.
你拉屎也是在创造肥料
So, it's important to think this way.
所以一定要这么想
You must never think that your life is useless.
你千万不要觉得自己的人生是没有用的
How could your life possibly be without value?
你自己的人生怎么可能没有用呢
Perhaps you were mass-produced.
也许你是被量产出来的
Maybe you've received very little love throughout your life.
对也许你从小到大得到的爱特别的少
Then give it to yourself.
那就自己给自己
Let's strengthen ourselves.
咱们就自己往自己加强啊
Transform yourself into a state of self-sufficiency.
把自己变成是一种具足的这种状态
Often, we can
很多的时候来讲
find some books on humanities and social sciences to read and gradually arm ourselves with Adlerian psychology don't be sad don't waste time being sad about anything you'll find that the things you lacked in childhood
咱们可以找一些人文社科的书看 用阿德勒心理学逐渐的武装自己 不要去难过 不要不要花那个时间难过任何的 你会发现你的这些童年缺失的这些东西
can all be found in books
都是可以在书籍当中找到的
truly enriching yourself
真正的丰富自己
I think you're very happy now
我觉得你现在就是很快乐
Then you can truly be happy
那你就真能快乐
There are many times
有很多的时候
That's why I say learning acting is particularly interesting
为什么我说学表演那东西特别有意思
It's about saying if you can do it, you can do it
就在于这就是说你行你就行
Even if you can't, it's still fine
不行也行
If they say you can't, then you can't
说你不行你就不行
Even if you can, it's still not good enough
行也不行
People sometimes in that moment
人有的时候在这一瞬间
Whether this life is painful or not
这一辈子痛苦不痛苦
It's all up to your parents
全是你爸你妈
and a word from your elementary school teacher
还有你小学老师一句话决定的
so let's turn it around for you now
所以咱现在就给你扭过来
let's straighten out all the things that have been twisted
咱把这个所有扭过来的这些东西都给你给掰
won't that solve the problem?
弄正了不就行了吗
give yourself a fresh system reboot
自己给自己重新刷一遍操作系统
reprogram your mind
重新洗一遍脑
don't find it troublesome
别觉得麻烦
don't think it's too painful
别觉得很痛苦
These things, you know,
这些东西来讲
have always been naturally present.
从来就是从来就是自然而然的应该存在的东西
You were already living a great life,
你本来你活的就很好
and what you did was truly remarkable.
你做的就很了不起
In what you're doing now,
你现在在做的事情上
either it leads to success, or there are some setbacks, some other things, because you have something better waiting for you. Your existence is a miracle. Your life is bound to be a legend.
要不就是通向成功 要不有一些失败 有一些那什么 这就是因为你有更好的东西在等待着你 你的存在就是一个奇迹 你的人生也必将是一个传奇
You can't see your life clearly right now.
你现在没有办法去看清自己的人生
What kind of life it is.
是什么样的啊
I didn't have a turn of luck until I was 37.
我37岁才转运
Does that mean I have to wait until I'm 36 or 35?
难道我三十六三十五
34?
三十三十三啊
The numbers from 27 to 28 are all mixed up.
二十七二十八的数字都乱了
Does this life have no meaning at all?
难道这生活就没有意义吗
Isn't it true that every day, every minute, every second makes up who I am at 37?
不每一天每一分每一秒才构成了37岁的我
Am I not living at 37?
我37岁就不活了吗
There's still 38,
还有38
39, 40,
三十九四十
So it doesn’t matter which stop this journey of life reaches,
所以人生这个旅程到哪一站没事
We will all eventually reach our destination.
最终都会到目的地的
No matter how we look at it,
咱们无论怎么样来讲
Let's support each other.
咱们啊互相支持
Our biological families might not be great
咱们这个原生家庭可能不好
but our cyber family can support each other
但是咱们赛博家庭可以互相支持
My videos
我的这些视频
to be honest, are quite powerful
说实在很多东西都是很有力量的
take your time to watch and absorb
慢慢看慢慢吸收
and slowly digest
慢慢消化
we'll gradually overcome those past toxic influences
咱们一点一点把过去的那种毒害你的那种
those Confucian, paternalistic
儒家式的那种家长式的
East Asian-style monster rooms
东亚式的怪物房
That kind of superior education that suppresses individuals
那种压制人的优质教育那种优势的啊
The Prussian method of cultivating people That way of belittling others That kind of pressure on individuals within collectivism Release all the emotional oppression It's fine
优记教育普鲁士人士的培养人的方式 那种轻看人的方式啊 那种集体主义中那种对个人的 那种情感上的压迫都给他释放出来 没有关系的
You can definitely do it
你一定可以做好
You didn't do well
你做不好
This is a lifetime
这也是一生
but no one will come to blame you
也没有任何人过来责备你
so your life has always had meaning
所以你的人生一直有意义的
your sole purpose
你的唯一的作用
is to experience joy in this world
你的唯一的东西就是来人间体验快乐的
there's still so much joy left to experience
还有很多快乐没体验到啊
the joy that Dad feels, you can't experience
爸爸的快乐你体验不到
so there's still a lot of joy for you to experience
所以还有很多快乐要体验
you're here to work happily
你来这儿就是来幸福的劳动啊
You need to achieve good results in what you do.
做事情得好成绩
These aren't things you were born to do.
这些都不是你天生就应该干的事儿
You were naturally meant to drop out.
你天生本来就应该辍学
What you truly need is sunshine, water, air, and sleep.
你真正需要的是阳光水空气跟睡眠
And of course.
还有那个对吧
And that handsome guy.
还有那个那个大帅哥
Just these things.
就这些东西
These are the things you need.
这才是你需要的东西啊
These are the things you truly need.
这才是你真正需要的东西
I can't live without these things anyway
我反正没有这些
I just can't survive
我就活不下去
You know that
你知道吗
These are the things truly needed for life
这些东西才是真正生活所需要的东西
What you need is praise from others
你需要的东西是别人的夸奖
Encouragement from others Just like what I'm giving you now You are a great person in and of yourself You are capable of living Being able to breathe Being able to exist is already being a good person It's not about what you have or haven't done
别人的鼓励 就像我现在的给你这些东西 你现在本身你就是一个很好的人 你能活着 能喘气 能存在就是一个很好的人 不是在于你做了什么没做什么
What you have or haven't bought
买了没买什么东西
Whether you've passed the civil service exam or not
考没考上公
Whether you've
考
failed the postgraduate exam or not
没考上研
These things don't matter
这些东西都不重要
As long as you're alive
只要活着
It's all good as long as we're alive
哥们儿活着就行
As long as we're alive, that's what matters
只要活着就行
Even if we die, we would still be heroes
死了咱们也是好样的
After we're gone
死了以后
We would have lived our lives to the fullest
咱们之前的人生咱也存在过了
So life is a journey
所以人生它就是一个旅程
It's an experience
它就是一个体验
It's nothing else
他别的什么都不是
You can make it whatever you want it to be
你愿意让他是什么
He is nothing
他就是什么
Because you are the Creator
因为你就是造物主
In your universe, you are
你本身在于你的宇宙来讲
You are the Creator
你就是造物主
Because you are both the Omega and the Alpha
因为一切你是omega也是阿尔法
You are the end of all things
你是一切的终结
And the beginning of all things
也是一切的开始
So everything is up to you
所以这东西任何事情你说了算
You are not an NPC
你不是什么NPC
You are the world.
你是这个世界
One day, after you awaken,
有一天你觉醒了以后
you will be the main character of this world.
你就是这个世界的主角啊
A true and real protagonist.
实实在在的主角
So I'm telling you,
所以我跟你说
if your child is in great pain,
如果你孩子很痛苦
what are you watching now?
你现在看什么
You can watch my videos,
可以看看我的视频
but more importantly,
但是更多的来讲
I hope you explore more areas, books on humanities and social sciences, psychology, social psychology, sociology, historiography, political science, take a look at all of them, and you'll find a lot of benefits yourself. It's not useless at all.
我希望你多涉猎一些啊 人文社科的书籍 心理学啊 社会心理学 社会学 历史学 政治学 你都看一看 你自己会感受到好的很多 它不是没有用的啊
The most important thing in life is to deceive yourself.
而人生最重要的就是要欺骗自己
To love dreaming.
要爱幻想
And to have dreams.
还有梦想啊
To make yourself feel really good.
要让自己感觉到非常的好啊
Although the material conditions might not be particularly good right now,
虽然现在物质条件可能不是特别的好
We can be spiritually rich.
但是咱们精神上可以做到很富足
We can have faith.
可以做到有信仰
That's how it is.
就是这样
So when you have faith,
所以你有了信仰
You also have strength.
你也就有了力量
What is my faith?
我的信仰是什么
Sunlight, water, and air—just that simple.
阳光水空气就这么简单
The visual novels I bought on Steam.
就是我steam上买的那些黄油
It's just that simple for me.
我就这么这么简单
I'm happy as long as I see a beautiful woman.
一个人我只要见到美女我就快乐
This is the meaning of my life.
这就是我活着的意义
It's about adding little sisters on WeChat.
就是小妹妹加薇薇
I'm just a very ordinary person.
我就是一个很俗的人
That's who I am.
我就是这样一个人
I'm 40 years old,
我到40岁了
And I'm still like this.
我也是这样
I'll be 88 and still like this.
我到88了我也是这样
Because this is me.
因为这就是我
This is the path of my life.
这就是我的人生的道路
Why?
为什么
Because this path is easy to achieve.
因为这种道路它容易实现
It's just that simple.
就这么简单
So no matter what,
所以无论怎么样
No matter how you want to live your life,
无论你想把人生过成什么样
Remember, you are the master of your life.
记住你是人生的主人
As long as you're happy, that's all that matters.
你快乐就对了